Jordan Briley

3917 Pepper Thorn Ave. Unit 102 North Las Vegas, NV 89081 (702) 427-5557 JBriley.0629@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Knowledgeable IT professional with over nine years of experience in a wide variety of technologies. Holds an active Department of Defense Secret security clearance. Successful in learning and comprehending new systems and methods and is able to make difficult decisions in stressful situations.

CERTIFICATIONS

Cisco Certified Entry Networking Technician (CCENT), CompTIA Security+, CompTIA Network+, CompTIA A+, currently working toward CCNA.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Network Hardware:

Cisco 2800, 3700 & 7200 series routers, Cisco 3500, 4500 & 6500 series switches, Cisco ASA 5505 & 5510, Cisco CallManager, Cisco 7900 series VoIP phones.

Encryption Hardware:

TACLANE Encryptor (KG-175), Electronic Transfer Device (KYK-13), ANCD (AN/CYZ-10) Data Transfer Device, SKL (AN/PYQ-10) Simple Key Loader, KIV-19 Cryptographic Link Encryption Device.

IPTV:

Comtech CMR-5975 Media Router S2 Receivers, Motorola DSR-4400, DSR-4410, & DSR-4410MD Integrated Receiver Decoders, Scientific Atlanta PowerVu Model D9850 Program Receiver, Wegener UNITY 4600 Professional Media Receiver, Adtec Digital DTA-3050 Digital Turn Around Media Router, Scientific Atlanta D9900 Digital Content Manager MPEG Processor.

Satellite Communications:

AN/TSC-167, AN/TSC-93, and AN/TSC-85 satellite terminals, Viasat Linkway Modem, Radyne DMD20 Universal Satellite Modem, Spectrum Analyzer.

Software:

Windows XP, Windows Vista, Windows 7, Microsoft Office, Cisco IOS, WhatsUp Gold, Pumpkin, Putty, Wireshark.

EDUCATION

Warrior Leader Course, U.S. Army - 2006 Supervisor Development Course, U.S. Army - 2005 Manager Development Course, U.S. Army - 2005 MOS 31S Satellite Communications Systems Course, U.S. Army - 2002

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Harris IT Services, Nellis AFB, NV - 2010-present Network Technician

Responsible for the support of design and operations of the network infrastructure. Participated in design reviews and implemented network infrastructure and services in support of simulated and real world Command and Control operations. Performed router and switch configuration. Managed all network devices and produced technical documents and network diagrams.

Intelsat General, Ellenwood, GA - 2009 Network Operations Center Technician

Controlled access to 50 domestic and international satellites. Proactively monitored the condition of military, government and commercial networks utilizing fault monitoring tools. Performed 1st level troubleshooting and diagnostic support with end customers at all skill levels and escalated problems to the appropriate internal or external departments. Performed detailed trouble ticket documentation.

CSI Digital, Portland, OR - 2008-2009

Network Engineer

Engineered IPTV Headends specific to customer wants and needs. Configured and tested demodulators, switches, receivers, and routers prior to deploying to field locations. Led an installation team to field sites to install headend equipment. Constructed 3.8 and 4.5 meter satellite antennas at customer locations. Integrated headend into customer's existing xDSL, HFC, or FTTx networks.

United States Army, Fort Stewart, GA/Iraq - 2006-2008 Senior Satellite Communications Systems Operator/Maintainer

Shift supervisor for a Joint Network Node, Satellite Transportable Terminal, and Command Post Node. Supervised and maintained over \$1,500,000 worth of equipment. Developed and implemented a training program for on-site personnel resulting in greatly increased overall site technical ability. Counseled and evaluated the performance of subordinates on a monthly basis.

United States Army, Fort Stewart, GA/Iraq - 2001-2006 Satellite Communications Systems Operator/Maintainer

Installed, operated, and maintained AN/TSC-93, AN/TSC-85, and AN-TSC-167 satellite terminals. Provided real-time voice and data communications for various subscribers. Performed multiple satellite accesses which included contacting appropriate satellite controllers to verify polarity isolation. Applied understanding of signal flow to troubleshoot and diagnose equipment problems using appropriate test, measurement, and diagnostic equipment (TMDE) to include spectrum analyzers, oscilloscopes, Fireberds, and multimeters.